<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SEGUE: Urban Economic Segregation</title>
    <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SEGUE: Urban Economic Segregation</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.erc-segue.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open government data on sociodemographics</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/data/opendata_govsociodemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/data/opendata_govsociodemo/</guid>
      <description>Data on sociodemographics has always been an important source for researchers to understand the past, current, and future of the human population. It has become increasingly available and accessible worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List of podcasts about inequality, cities and segregation</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/podcast/</guid>
      <description>InequaliTalks&#xA;&amp;ldquo;InequaliTalks presents accessible research done by young economists on one of the most pressing issues in the public conversation: inequality.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;For our project, it is particularly relevant in terms of econometric methods and the topic of economic inequality. cf. Episode 7 on Wealth Inequality and Housing with Clara Martínez-Toledano and Episode 5 on Global Land Inequality with Yajna Govind.&#xA;The City Road podcast&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Informed stories about cities and urban life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERC SEGUE Team at the eX Modelo Workshop in the Paris, France 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/exmole23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/exmole23/</guid>
      <description>SEGUE @ ODISSEI Conference for Social Science in the Netherlands 2023 On November 13th and 14th, 2023, our team member, Bayi Li, participated in a teaching workshop on modelling and simulation. The workshop aimed to empower participants to explore and validate their agent-based models.&#xA;The workshop, led by a team of researchers with recognised expertise in interdisciplinary practices, provided step-by-step advanced methods for model exploration over the first two days. Prior to this, theoretical courses were conducted to explain what Agent-Based Modelling (ABM) is, its purpose, and the characteristics of a good model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERC SEGUE Team at the ODISSEI Conference for Social Science in the Netherlands 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/odissei23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/odissei23/</guid>
      <description>SEGUE @ ODISSEI Conference for Social Science in the Netherlands 2023 This November, two of our members took part in the ODISSEI Conference for Social Science in the Netherlands 2023. This event aimed to unite a community of computational social scientists for discussions on topics such as data, methodologies, infrastructure, ethics, and theoretical aspects linked to the use of digital and computational techniques in social science research. ODISSEI, which serves as the research infrastructure for social science in the Netherlands, facilitates the connection of researchers with essential data, knowledge, and tools, enabling them to conduct innovative research and embrace the computational dimension in their social inquiries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slides at ECTQG 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/research/ectqg23reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/research/ectqg23reports/</guid>
      <description>Keynote Talk by Clémentine Cottineau: Modelling urban economic segregation: a theoretical and quantitative quest Unable to display PDF file. Download instead.&#xA;Parallel Session by Bayi Li: A Review of the Design and Insights of Agent-based Model Frameworks on Urban Economic Segregation Move your cursor above the following slide, left click to activate it and use the &amp;lt;- and -&amp;gt; on your keyboard to switch page:&#xA;Parallel Session by Javier San Millán: Unveiling the Urban Divide: Novel Insights into Economic Segregation Using Fine- Grained Data Unable to display PDF file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERC Segue team at ECTQG 2023 in Braga</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/ectqg23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/ectqg23/</guid>
      <description>SEGUE @ European Colloquium on Theoretical and Quantitative Geography 2023 ECTQG’23 will take place in Braga (Portugal) between 14 and 17 September 2023, being organized by CITTA – the Research Centre for Territory, Transport and Environment of the Universities of Coimbra and Porto (https://citta.fe.up.pt/). It will be the 23rd edition of a prestigious conference series initiated in 1978 within which a wide variety of themes is addressed, such as epistemology and theory, geographic information science, geo-visualisation, spatial statistics, spatial interactions, networks, big geo-data, agent-based models, computer simulations, artificial life and intelligence, time geography, geo-history/archaeology, urban patterns and growth, fractals, scaling laws, economic geography, environmental and social sustainability, climate change, health geography, and transport and land use</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral position on policy evaluation and modelling</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/postdoc_jd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/postdoc_jd/</guid>
      <description>We have a 2-year postdoctoral position opening in the group!&#xA;Please consider it if you are a social scientist with experience in policy analysis and quantitative methods, as well as a strong interest in working together to build evidence on how to effectively reduce urban economic segregation and its consequences. Please find more relevant information in the job description below and apply by 31 October 2023 on the application platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utility-based Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/uitilitydecisionmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/uitilitydecisionmaking/</guid>
      <description>Utility-based decision making is one of the most prominent theories applied in Agent-Based Modelling (ABM), especially in discrete choice modelling. In this webpost, Bayi Li describes two common extended utility theories.&#xA;Related terms Utility&#xA;Utility, in economics, refers to the satisfaction or benefit an individual receives from the consumption of goods or services (The Investopedia Team, 2022). Marshall (1890) broaden the definition that utility is the fulfilment or satisfaction of a desire, expanding the context to all possible motives to human action (Moscati, 2020).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reporting on the event dedicated to synthetic data at CBS</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/synthetischedata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/synthetischedata/</guid>
      <description>Symposium Synthetische Data Synthetic data simulate the joint characteristics of the relationships between people and objects (e.g. a school or a neighbourhood), thus allowing the simulation of reality without identifying the person or object. Synthetic data can be generated by an algorithm or a computer simulation. The advantage of synthetic data is that, depending on the purpose of the user, a trade-off is made between the analytical value of the dataset and the disclosure risk</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rich and poor: same city, different neighborhoods?</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/spain_seg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/blog/spain_seg/</guid>
      <description>The “Ricos y pobres: ¿misma ciudad, distintos barrios?” project is an online tool that visually shows the evolution of urban economic segregation in more than 2000 municipalities of Spain. Using income data per census tract from the Spanish Statistical Agency, the extent of segregation among the richest and poorest groups of all cities of the country with available information were calculated for the 2015-2020 period. This tool allows the user to check the segregation levels of their municipality of choice through a set of maps, graphs and automatically-generated summary reports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Reading Lists</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/research/readinglist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/research/readinglist/</guid>
      <description>Our reading list Here are the books on our desks waiting for some reading time:&#xA;Manzo, G. (2022). Agent-based Models and Causal Inference. John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons. Molander, P. (2022). The Origins of Inequality: Mechanisms, Models, Policy. Springer Nature. Secchi, B. (2021). La ciudad de los ricos y la ciudad de los pobres. Los libros de la Catarata. Van Ham, M., Tammaru, T., Ubarevičienė, R., &amp;amp; Janssen, H. (2021). Urban socio-economic segregation and income inequality: A global perspective (p.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About SEGUE</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/about/</guid>
      <description>ERC Project on modelling urban economic segregation&#xA;The uneven concentration of economic resources in cities hampers the well-being and opportunities of poorer citizens and represents a threat to social cohesion. It is considered a major policy challenge by researchers and international institutions alike. Our aim with the SEGUE project is to identify and model the combination of major economic, geographic, sociological and demographical drivers of urban economic segregation in order to better understand its dynamics and to better assess possible remediatory policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.erc-segue.nl/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.erc-segue.nl/contact/</guid>
      <description>To contact us, please fill out the form below.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
